<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document url="http://www.openejb.org/index.xml">
  <body>
    <title>CMP Database Files</title>
    <section title="Database files">
      <p>
      Each CMP Container you declare in your openejb.conf file requires two Castor JDO <a href="http://www.castor.org/database-conf.html">database files</a> to be created.
      <ul>
        <li>A Local_TX_Database file</li>
        <li>A Global_TX_Database file</li>
      </ul>
      </p>


    <section title="Local TX database file">
      <p>
      Each CMP container will need a Local_TX_Database file.  This file 
      specifies the configuration for 
      <ul>
      <li>Obtaining <b>direct</b> database connections</li>
      <li>Any number of mapping.xml schema files</li>
      </ul>
      </p>
      <p>
      This file is used when non-transactional connections are needed to the database.
      This is when the TransactionManager is not managing the transaction, 
      such as when the tx attribute of the EntityBean method is Supports 
      (with no client tx), NotSupported, or Never. 
      </p>
      <p>
      Supports, NotSupported and Never refer to the container-managed 
      transaction attributes defined be the EJB specification.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section title="Global TX database file">
      <p>
      Each CMP container will need a Global_TX_Database file.  This file 
      specifies the configuration for 
      <ul>
      <li>Obtaining <b>managed</b> database connections</li>
      <li>The same mapping files as the Local_TX_Database file</li>
      </ul>
      </p>
      <p>
      This file is used when transactional connections are needed to the database.
      This is when the TransactionManager is managing the transaction, 
      such as when the tx attribute of the EntityBean method is Supports (client has tx), 
      RequiresNew, Required or Manditory. 
      </p>
      <p>
      Supports, RequiresNew, Required and Manditory refer to the 
      container-managed transaction attributes defined be the EJB specification.
      </p>
    </section>
    </section>

    <section title="Setting the 'engine' attribute">
      <p>In both these files there is an <b>engine</b> attribute which tells 
      Castor JDO what database you are working with.  This allows
      it to take care of database specific aspects of persisting data to the database.
      </p>
      <p>
        See this doc for a of supported databases.<br/>
<a href="http://www.castor.org/database-conf.html">http://www.castor.org/database-conf.html</a>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
