<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- $Id$ -->
<document url="http://openejb.sf.net/index.xml" toc="none">
  <body>
    <title>OpenEJB -- Open Source EJB Container System</title>


    <section title="Welcome to OpenEJB!">
    <p>
    OpenEJB is an open source, modular, configurable, and extendable EJB Container
    System and EJB Server.
    </p>
    <p> 
    We are building the hottest EJB container system in the world! Why?  Because
    OpenEJB is whatever you want it to be. The design is radically different than 
    anything else available today.  <a href="pluggable.html">Everything in OpenEJB 
    is pluggable, even OpenEJB itself.</a>
    </p>
    <p> 
    If you've got the guts to think differently, and the brains to make a difference, 
    then we dare you to join us. We double dog dare you! 
    </p>
 
    <section title="EJB Server">
    <p>
    OpenEJB comes with fast, lightweight EJB Servers for both
    <a href="embedded.html">Local</a> and <a href="remote-server.html">Remote</a>
    access. That's right, <a href="deploy.html">deploy</a> your EJBs into the 
    container system, then just <a href="start-command.html">start the 
    Remote EJB Server</a> from the command line! Or, put OpenEJB in your class
    path and use it as <a href="embedded.html">an embedded library</a> through 
    the Local EJB Server.
    </p>
    </section>

    <section title="EJB Container System">
    <p>
    As a <a href="containersystem.html">container system</a>, OpenEJB works like 
    a big plug-in for middleware servers like Web servers, CORBA servers, and 
    application servers. By plugging in OpenEJB these servers obtain instant 
    EJB compliance for hosting Enterprise JavaBeans! 
    </p>
    <p>
    OpenEJB is designed for speed and low resource consumption making it a very 
    desirable alternative for middleware providers who want EJB 1.1 compatibility. 
    OpenEJB is already shipping in platforms like Apple Computer's 
    <a href="http://www.apple.com/webobjects/">WebObjects</a>,
    Exolab's <a href="http://openccm.exolab.org">OpenCCM</a>, and 
    <a href="http://openorb.sf.net">OpenORB</a>.  
    </p>
    <p>
    OpenEJB is targeted for other middleware platforms including another commercial 
    application server called  <a href="http://www.intalio.com">n3 </a>, 
    the <a href="http://jakarta.apache.org">Apache Tomcat</a> server, 
    and <a href="http://jakarta.apache.org/avalon/phoenix/index.html">Avalon Phoenix</a>.
    </p>

    </section>


    <section title="Who is working on OpenEJB ?">
    <p>
    OpenEJB is the brainchild of Richard Monson-Haefel and David Blevins.  
    </p>
    <p>
    Richard is author of <a href="http://www.oreilly.com/catalog/entjbeans3">Enterprise JavaBeans, 3rd Edition</a> (O'Reilly 2001) 
    and co-author of <a href="http://www.oreilly.com/catalog/javmesser">Java Message Service</a> (O'Reilly 2000).  
    </p>
    <p>
    David Blevins is author of 'Understanding J2EE' a forthcoming Addison-Wesley book on the Java 2 Enterprise 
    Edition, and contributing author to the book 'Component-Based Software Engineering' (Addison-Wesley 2001). 
    <br/><br/>
    </p>

    </section>
  </section>

  </body>
</document>
