<news-section>
  <news>
    <url>http://www.mail-archive.com/openejb-user%40lists.sourceforge.net/msg00971.html</url>    
    <title>OpenEJB moves to Codehaus</title>  
    <author>dblevins</author> 
    <date>Thursday, March 4 2004</date>   
    <time>4:32</time>   
    <summary>
We have recently changed hosting services from SourceForge.net
(sf.net) to Codehaus (<a href="http://www.codehaus.org">codehaus.org</a>).  Codehaus is a smaller community
of peers and is able to offer much more trust and control to projects
than sf.net.  At Codehaus, we are now able to fully setup and leverage
the openejb.org domain.
    </summary>
  </news>
  <news>
    <url>https://sourceforge.net/forum/forum.php?forum_id=329586</url>    
    <title>OpenEJB to be certified with Apache Geronimo</title>  
    <author>dblevins</author> 
    <date>Monday, November 17 2003</date>   
    <time>4:32</time>   
    <summary>
Two ground-breaking announcements were made during the Geronimo session at ApacheCon today. 
First, the Apache Software Foundation will license the TCK from Sun to test and officially release 
Geronimo as a certified J2EE 1.4 application server. Secondly, the critical EJB 2.1 container functionality 
will be provided by OpenEJB.    
   </summary>
    </news>
  <news>
    <url>http://sourceforge.net/forum/forum.php?forum_id=279555</url>    
    <title>OpenEJB at Borland Developer Days 2003 in Poland</title>  
    <author>dblevins</author> 
    <date>Thursday, June 5 2003</date>   
    <time>3:53</time>   
    <summary>
Our own Jacek Laskowski will be heading up a session about OpenEJB during BDD 2003 in Warsaw (Poland)
<br/><br/>
This is a follow-up to his article about OpenEJB-Tomcat integration. The session will also cover using JBuilder to run and debug applications built on OpenEJB. 
    </summary>
    </news>
  <news>
    <url>http://sourceforge.net/forum/forum.php?forum_id=281244</url>    
    <title>The IDE &amp; App server plug-in challenge</title>  
    <author>dblevins</author> 
    <date>Friday, May 30 2003</date>   
    <time>09:21</time>   
    <summary>
As a pluggable EJB Container system, there are a great number of places that OpenEJB could be plugged into; IDE's, App Servers, even your own standalone programs.
<br/><br/>
So, here is the challenge; plug OpenEJB into an app server or IDE of your choice and report the outcome to the user list. We'll collect the data and put it on the website.
<br/><br/>Read the full news story for instructions!
    </summary>
  </news>
  <news>
    <url>http://sourceforge.net/forum/forum.php?forum_id=279555</url>    
    <title>New CMP Guide</title>  
    <author>dblevins</author> 
    <date>Saturday, May 24 2003</date>   
    <time>12:43</time>   
    <summary>
We've put together a one-stop-shop CMP guide that highlights all 
the fundamental CMP concepts. Contributions are welcome!<br/><br/>
<a href="http://openejb.sourceforge.net/cmp_guide.html">CMP Guide</a>
    </summary>
    </news>
    <news>
      <url>http://sourceforge.net/forum/forum.php?forum_id=252448</url>    
      <title>O'Reilly article on OpenEJB and Tomcat</title>  
      <author>dblevins</author> 
      <date>Thursday, February 13 2003</date>   
      <time>12:43</time>   
      <summary>
        A new article on the O'Reilly Network features the new OpenEJB 0.9.1 and Tomcat 4.1.18
        integration. Several new details about to integration are covered, plus new info on the
        TomcatEjbFactory. Overall, it's a must read for those looking to combine Servlets with
        EJBs. 
      </summary>
   </news>
   <news>
      <url>http://sourceforge.net/forum/forum.php?forum_id=228317</url>    
      <title>OpenEJB 0.9.0 Released</title>  
      <author>dblevins</author> 
      <date>Tuesday, November 19 2002</date>   
      <time>06:24</time>   
      <summary>OpenEJB is a pre-built, self-contained, portable EJB container system that can be plugged into any server environment including app servers, Web servers, J2EE platforms, CORBA ORBs, databases, etc.  The 0.9.0 release of OpenEJB features easy Tomcat integration via OpenEJB Loader Servlet, additional configuration flexibility, and EJB validation tools.</summary>
   </news>
   <news>
       <url>http://java.foundries.sourceforge.net/article.pl?sid=02/10/05/0841240&amp;mode=thread&amp;tid=49&amp;tid=52</url>
       <title>OpenEJB Thanks Community</title>
       <author>dblevins</author> 
       <date>Saturday, October 5, 2002</date>   
       <time>10:17</time>   
       <summary>
           The OpenEJB project has received such tremendous community support since our 0.8 Final release,
          it's time to say thank you to our community and give credit where credit is due. The amount of
          suggestions, feedback and contributions that have come in is overwhelming, it has been hard at
          work keeping pace. OpenEJB team has been working full-steam implementing your suggestion and
          improving the usability and performance of OpenEJB. The result is something we are all very proud
          of and represents a real community effort.
       </summary>
   </news>
   <news>
      <url>http://java.foundries.sourceforge.net/article.pl?sid=02/05/27/2335209&amp;mode=thread&amp;tid=49</url>    
      <title>OpenEJB 0.8 Released</title>  
      <author>dblevins</author> 
      <date>Monday, May 27, 2002</date>   
      <time>13:27</time>   
      <summary>
        OpenEJB has been an open source EJB Container-only project for two years and has received great
        support from vendors like Apple Computer. As of 0.8, OpenEJB comes with fast, lightweight EJB
        Servers for both Local and Remote access
      </summary>
   </news>

   <news>
   <url>http://sourceforge.net/forum/forum.php?forum_id=145295</url>    
   <title>Apple's WebObjects 5.1 featuring EJB support via OpenEJB</title>  
   <author>dblevins</author> 
   <date>Thursday, January 17, 2002</date>   
   <time>15:46</time>   
   <summary>
     Apple Computer's WebObjects 5.1 was released today with an exciting new 
     feature, EJB support! The new 5.1 release features a stand-alone Pure Java
     application server built on OpenEJB (EJB 1.1), Tyrex (JTA/JTS), and 
     OpenORB (RMI-IIOP). 
   </summary>
</news>

   
</news-section>
