
<news-section>
	<!-- $Id$ -->
    <news>
      <url>http://sourceforge.net/forum/forum.php?forum_id=252448</url>    
      <title>O'Reilly article on OpenEJB and Tomcat</title>  
      <author>dblevins</author> 
      <date>Thursday, February 13 2003</date>   
      <time>12:43</time>   
      <summary>
        A new article on the O'Reilly Network features the new OpenEJB 0.9.1 and Tomcat 4.1.18
        integration. Several new details about to integration are covered, plus new info on the
        TomcatEjbFactory. Overall, it's a must read for those looking to combine Servlets with
        EJBs. 
      </summary>
   </news>
    <news>
      <url>http://sourceforge.net/forum/forum.php?forum_id=251807</url>    
      <title>BUGFIX: Entity remove with no TX</title>  
      <author>dblevins</author> 
      <date>Wednesday, February 12 2003</date>   
      <time>09:54</time>   
      <summary>Several people have written in about the remove method of CMP EntityBeans not working correctly when there is not transaction in progress.  Jacek Laskowski, the author of our wonderful CMP documentation, has found and fixed the problem.  Thanks Jacek!</summary>
   </news>
   <news>
      <url>http://sourceforge.net/forum/forum.php?forum_id=228317</url>    
      <title>OpenEJB 0.9.0 Released</title>  
      <author>dblevins</author> 
      <date>Tuesday, November 19 2002</date>   
      <time>06:24</time>   
      <summary>OpenEJB is a pre-built, self-contained, portable EJB container system that can be plugged into any server environment including app servers, Web servers, J2EE platforms, CORBA ORBs, databases, etc.  The 0.9.0 release of OpenEJB features easy Tomcat integration via OpenEJB Loader Servlet, additional configuration flexibility, and EJB validation tools.</summary>
   </news>
   <news>
       <url>http://java.foundries.sourceforge.net/article.pl?sid=02/10/05/0841240&amp;mode=thread&amp;tid=49&amp;tid=52</url>
       <title>OpenEJB Thanks Community</title>
       <author>dblevins</author> 
       <date>Saturday, October 5, 2002</date>   
       <time>10:17</time>   
       <summary>
           The OpenEJB project has received such tremendous community support since our 0.8 Final release,
          it's time to say thank you to our community and give credit where credit is due. The amount of
          suggestions, feedback and contributions that have come in is overwhelming, it has been hard at
          work keeping pace. OpenEJB team has been working full-steam implementing your suggestion and
          improving the usability and performance of OpenEJB. The result is something we are all very proud
          of and represents a real community effort.
       </summary>
   </news>
   <news>
      <url>http://java.foundries.sourceforge.net/article.pl?sid=02/05/27/2335209&amp;mode=thread&amp;tid=49</url>    
      <title>OpenEJB 0.8 Released</title>  
      <author>dblevins</author> 
      <date>Monday, May 27, 2002</date>   
      <time>13:27</time>   
      <summary>
        OpenEJB has been an open source EJB Container-only project for two years and has received great
        support from vendors like Apple Computer. As of 0.8, OpenEJB comes with fast, lightweight EJB
        Servers for both Local and Remote access
      </summary>
   </news>

   <news>
   <url>http://sourceforge.net/forum/forum.php?forum_id=145295</url>    
   <title>Apple's WebObjects 5.1 featuring EJB support via OpenEJB</title>  
   <author>dblevins</author> 
   <date>Thursday, January 17, 2002</date>   
   <time>15:46</time>   
   <summary>
     Apple Computer's WebObjects 5.1 was released today with an exciting new 
     feature, EJB support! The new 5.1 release features a stand-alone Pure Java
     application server built on OpenEJB (EJB 1.1), Tyrex (JTA/JTS), and 
     OpenORB (RMI-IIOP). 
   </summary>
</news>

   
</news-section>
