<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- $Id$ -->
<document url="http://openejb.sf.net/quickstart.xml" toc="numeric">
  <body>
    <title>OpenEJB QuickStart Guide</title>

    <section title="Installation" ref-id="getopenejb">
    
<p>To install OpenEJB, simply <a 
href="http://openejb.sf.net/download.html">download the latest release</a> 
and unpack your zip or tar.gz into the directory where you want OpenEJB to 
live.</p>  

<p>Windows users can download the zip and unpack it with the WinZip 
program.</p> <p>Linux users can download the tar.gz and unpack it with the 
following command:</p> 

<p><command>
tar xzvf openejb-0.8.3.tar.gz
</command></p>

<p>Congradulations, you've installed OpenEJB.</p>

<note>If you are on Mac OS X and have downloaded the tar.gz, don't 
bother trying to unpack it with anything other than the above tar 
command, it won't work.</note>
    <p>
 If you've unpacked OpenEJB into the directory C:\openejb, for example, 
 than this directory is your OPENEJB_HOME directory.  The OPENEJB_HOME
 directory is refered to in various parts of the documentation, so it's
 good to remeber where it is.
    </p>
</section>
    
<section title="Using OpenEJB" ref-id="getopenejb">
    <p>
 Now all you need to do is move to the OPENEJB_HOME directory, the 
 directory where OpenEJB was unpacked, and type:
</p>
<p><command>openejb help</command></p>
 
<p>
 For Windows users, that looks like this:
</p>
  
<p><command>C:\openejb> openejb help</command></p>
   
 
<p>
 For UNIX/Linux/Mac OS X users, that looks like this:
</p>
 
<p><command>[user@host openejb]# ./openejb.sh help</command></p>
   
 
<p>
 You really only need to know two commands to use OpenEJB, deploy
 and start.  Both are completely documented and have examples.
</p>
 
<p>
 For help information and command options, try this:
</p>
 
<p><command>openejb deploy -help</command><br/>
   <command>openejb start -help</command></p>
   
   
 
<p>
 For examples on using the command and options, try this:
</p>
 
<p><command>openejb deploy -examples</command><br/>
   <command>openejb start -examples</command></p>
 
<p>
 That's it!
</p>

<p>
If you don't have any EJBs or clients to run, try the ubiquitous 
<a href="hello-world.html">Hello World</a> example.
</p>
    
    </section>
    
    <section title="Join the mailing list" ref-id="joinlist">
        
    <p>
    The OpenEJB User list is where the general OpenEJB community goes to ask 
    questions, make suggestions, chat with other users, and keep a finger on 
    the pulse of the project.
    </p>
            
    <p>
    Please feel free to ask as many questions as you need while becoming 
    familiar with the project.  We believe the perspective of those who are new 
    the project is very valuable and we rely on your feedback to make the 
    project easier to use and understand for everyone.  If you have any 
    suggestions on ways we can help those that are new to the project get up to 
    speed more quickly, we are more than willing to listen.
    </p>
        
    <p>
    <a href="http://lists.sourceforge.net/lists/listinfo/openejb-user">Subscribe</a>/<a href="http://www.geocrawler.com/redir-sf.php3?list=openejb-user">View Archive</a>        
    </p>
    
    </section>
    
  </body>
</document>
