<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document url="http://openejb.sf.net/quickstart.xml" toc="numeric">
  <body>
    <title>OpenEJB QuickStart Guide</title>

    <section title="Abstract" ref-id="abstract">
        
    <p>
    This document is a slightly verbose quickstart, if you are not interested in all
    the chat and simply want the bare minimum, we offer a 
    <a href="commands-only-windows.html">Commands-Only Guide for Windows Users</a> and a 
    <a href="commands-only-linux.html">Commands-Only Guide for Linux/Unix/Mac OS X Users</a>
    </p>
            
    </section>
    
    <section title="Join the mailing list" ref-id="joinlist">
        
    <p>
    The OpenEJB User list is where the general OpenEJB community goes to ask 
    questions, make suggestions, chat with other users, and keep a finger on 
    the pulse of the project.
    </p>
            
    <p>
    Please feel free to ask as many questions as you need while becoming 
    familiar with the project.  We believe the perspective of those who are new 
    the project is very valuable and we rely on your feedback to make the 
    project easier to use and understand for everyone.  If you have any 
    suggestions on ways we can help those that are new to the project get up to 
    speed more quickly, we are more than willing to listen.
    </p>
        
    <p>
    <a href="http://lists.sourceforge.net/lists/listinfo/openejb-user">Subscribe</a>/<a href="http://www.geocrawler.com/redir-sf.php3?list=openejb-user">View Archive</a>        
    </p>
    
    </section>
    
    <section title="Get OpenEJB" ref-id="getopenejb">
    
    <p>
    <a href="download.html">Download</a> and unpack the latest release. Or,
    checkout the source from CVS and <a href="quickstart-buildit.html">build it</a>.
    </p>
    </section>
    
    <section title="Run the test suite (optional)" ref-id="runtests">
    <p>
    Now that you have download or built OpenEJB, it's a
    good to run the test suite and verify that everything is setup.
    Execute the following commands:
    </p>
    
    <p>
    Windows:<br></br>
    <command>C:\somewhere> cd c:\openejb</command><br/>
    <command>C:\openejb> openejb test</command>
    </p>
    <p>  
    Unix/Linux/Mac OS X:<br></br>
    <command>[user@host somewhere]# cd /openejb </command><br/>
    <command>[user@host openejb]#  ./openejb.sh test</command>
    </p>
    
    </section>
    
    <section title="Deploy your ejb-jar" ref-id="deployjar">
    <p>
    OpenEJB comes with a command-line tool to help guide you through deploying
    your jars in OpenEJB.  The options are as follows:
    </p>
    
    <p>
    Windows:<br></br>
    <command>C:\openejb> openejb deploy <i>yourEjb.jar</i></command>
    </p>
    
    <p>  
    Unix/Linux/Mac OS X:<br></br>
    <command>[user@host openejb]# ./openejb.sh deploy <i>yourEjb.jar</i></command>
    </p>
    
    <p>
    If you don't have any EJBs or clients to run, try the ubiquitous 
    <a href="hello-world.html">Hello World</a> example.
    </p>
    </section>

  </body>
</document>
