<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document url="http://www.openejb.org/index.xml" toc="none" page-title="none">

  <body>
    <title>OpenEJB -- Project Status</title>

<section title="Activity"><p>
All the team works on OpenEJB and Geronimo, so
we are a little stretched.  We've been putting a lot of work into
Geronimo and an EJB 2.1 version of OpenEJB (OpenEJB 2.0) and still
poking at OpenEJB 1.0 (the next logical release after 0.9.2) which
needs more testing and documentation
before a final can be cut.
    </p>
</section>

<section title="Releases">
    <p>
One of the major questions people have is "why haven't there been any releases since 0.9.2?"
    </p>
    <p>
Fair question.  Really, there have been three major releases of OpenEJB in the last year; Geronimo 1.0 M1, Geronimo 1.0 M2, and Geronimo 1.0 M3.  All those releases were cut by myself (David Blevins) and Dain Sundstrom and included major EJB 2.1 accomplishments developed by everyone on the OpenEJB team.  See the 2.0 details below for more details.
    </p>
    <p>
There haven't been any releases in the 1.0 branch of OpenEJB primarily because the whole team has been working on the 2.0 branch and because there haven't been any major issues with OpenEJB 0.9.2 which is a very solid EJB 1.1 release--that is till Tomcat 5.5 came along.  Tomcat 5.5 changed some of the API's we used to integrate OpenEJB into Tomcat, so there is much more of a push to get OpenEJB 1.0 out the door.
    </p>
</section>
<section title="OpenEJB 1.0">
<p>
  OpenEJB 1.0 wil be the next release after 0.9.2.
  Everything that 0.9.2 supports will be
  supported in 1.0.  EJB 1.1 compliant.  To be released as soon
  as we get the one-OpenEJB-per-webapp feature tested and documented.
  There have also been some changes in Tomcat 5.5 which require some
  changes in OpenEJB.
</p>
<p><a href="status-1.0.html">1.0 status and details</a></p>
<p>
CVS info:<br/>cvs co openejb1
</p>
</section>

<section title="OpenEJB 2.0">
<p>
  OpenEJB 2.0 code it to become EJB 2.1 compliant.
  Doesn't yet support embedding in Tomcat, or the openejb.conf file
  structure.  When we get further along we will add those features back
  in--it's a fair amount of work.  There won't be any official 2.0
  releases until we get that stuff back in.
</p>
    <p><a href="status-2.0.html">2.0 status and details</a></p>
    <p>
    CVS info:<br/>cvs co openejb
    </p>
</section>

  </body>
</document>
