<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- $Id$ -->
<document url="http://openejb.sf.net/index.xml" toc="none">
  <body>
    <title>OpenEJB -- Open Source EJB Container System</title>


    <section title="Why OpenEJB?">
<p> 
OpenEJB provides vendors with compliance to the latest EJB specification at a lower opportunity cost than could possibly be achieved by one vendor alone.
</p> 

<p> 
Each vendor relying on OpenEJB, in return sponsors development and maintenance on a limited basis.  Each vendor also contributes patches, enhancements, or feedback resulting from their own QA testing and customer feedback, leading to a higher quality EJB implementation than is otherwise achievable.
</p> 

<p> 
The result is a community implementation of a community defined specification.  This leaves your resources free to create QoSs and proprietary technology around and beside the standard technology customers want.  The bottom line, increased ability to compete at a lower cost.
</p> 

<p> 
OpenEJB is a standard implementation of a standardized technology that companies can leverage to stay with the current market trends while simultaneously focusing internal resources on its own proprietary technologies and unique Quality of Services (QoSs).  The risk involved in outsourcing the development of technology is considerably lower when that technology is standardized, all requirements for that technology are completely defined and all design flaws are flushed out before the spec is finalized.  While there is some room to provide vendor specific QoSs in a standardized technology like EJB, these are usually minor or side areas leaving the core of the technology rigidly defined.  It makes perfect sense to leverage a standard implementation of the core technology, OpenEJB, and instead, focus all internal resources on QoSs and other proprietary technical areas.  It makes even more sense when other vendors are sharing in the cost involved to sponsor projects like OpenEJB.  
</p> 

<p> 
It makes little sense to spend your internal resources implementing your own version of a standardized technology, the customer's view of the technology is also standardized and they will have little reason to choose your implementation over the competition's unless you can offer more QoSs or additional technology or a lower price.  Internal resources are better spent focusing one or all three of these areas, compliance with the latest craze technology can be achieved at no internal cost and low financial cost by leveraging OpenEJB.
</p> 
</section>

<section title="">
<p> 
For more information, contact:<br/>
<a href="mailto:David.Blevins@visi.com">David Blevins</a><br/>
OpenEJB Project Lead<br/>
</p> 

</section>
</body>
</document>
