<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document url="http://www.openejb.org/index.xml" toc="none" page-title="none">

  <body>
    <title>OpenEJB 2.0 Status</title>


<section title="New Features">
    <p>
    OpenEJB 2.0 is still in heavy development.  Notable things new in 2.0 include:
      <ul>
      <li>EJB 2.1 support</li>
      <li>Embraces GBean IoC Kernel</li>
      </ul>
    </p>
    <section title="EJB 2.1 support">
    <p>
    Basic implementation of all the EJB 2.1 set is present minus EJB-QL, WebServices, and CORBA support.  All of which are being actively worked on.
    </p>
    </section>
    <section title="Embraces GBean IoC Kernel">
    <p>
    OpenEJB is one of the first projects to fully embrace the Geronimo GBean Kernel architecture.  As an early adopter, we were are and are subject to rolling with constant change in the GBean concept.  However, this new concept has really become simple and elegant.  It's use in OpenEJB will allow users to not only embed OpenEJB as was previously possible, but will also allow:
        <ul>
        <li>Integrators/Embedders to tightly integrate with other components in the target platform.</li>
        <li>Users to reconfigure and deploy into running servers</li>
        </ul>
    Both items are absolutely in-step with the OpenEJB goals and will allow that functionality to be achieved without loosing simplicity.
    </p>
    </section>
</section>

<section title="Compatibility Goals">
<p>
Support for the OpenEJB 1.0 config files in OpenEJB 2.0 comes and goes but will eventually be put
back in permanently and released as an official OpenEJB 2.0 release.
It's actually been unofficially released with Geronimo 1.0 M1, M2 and M3 already,
but the main features of OpenEJB (embeddability and simple configuration) are not yet there.
</p>
</section>

<section title="Release schedule">
<p>
As soon as embedded testing, Tomcat integration, and simple configuration support is restored in the 2.0 codebase, there will be the first of the official OpenEJB 2.0 releases.  Anyone not interested in those features just wanting raw EJB 2.1 support can download any of the <a href="http://geronimo.apache.org/download.html">Geronimo 1.0 milestones</a>.
</p>
</section>


  </body>
</document>


