<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- $Id$ -->
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>OpenEJB CMP Mapping</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <title>OpenEJB CMP Mapping</title>

    <section title="Preface">

      <p>
      The OpenEJB CMP Container is no simple container.  Unlike most CMP 1.1 
      containers, which simply generate BMP code for you and cannot handle 
      complex object-to-relational (O/R) mapping, the OpenEJB CMP Container 
      does all of that and more.  It supports very complicated O/R mapping 
      and can map an entity bean across several tables and dependent objects.  
      It also supports the OMG's Object Query Language (OQL) which gives your 
      ejbFind methods added power.
      </p>

      <p>
      All of this is done through the power of Castor JDO, a project that has been 
      developed since day one to be the most sophisticated CMP Container ever created.
      Castor fulfills that role in spades and has become one of the most popular 
      object-to-relational and object-to-xml tools in the commercial or open source 
      world.
      </p>

      <p>This document details the full syntax of Castor's O/R mapping ability, it is 
      not for the weak of heart.  For a simple introduction to OpenEJB CMP and the 
      related Castor mapping.xml files, see this wonderful doc written by Jacek Laskowski, 
      <a href="cmp_entity_postgresql.xml">CMP Hello World.</a>
      </p>

      <p>OpenEJB would like to thank the whole Castor team for their great work and to 
      <a href="mailto:ferret@frii.com">Bruce Snyder</a> for writing this very thorough 
      doc on the syntax of the mapping.xml file used for entity-to-relational mapping.
      </p>

    </section>

    <section title="Introduction">
      <p>
      Castor mapping files are used by the OpenEJB CMP Container to provide a mechanism 
      for binding a Java object model (an EntityBean and it's Java objects) to a 
      relational database model. This is usually referred to as object-to-relational 
      mapping (O/R mapping). O/R mapping bridges the gap between an object model and a 
      relational model. 
      </p>

      <p>
      The following is a high-level example of a mapping file: 
      </p>

      <code>
      &lt;mapping>
          &lt;class>
              &lt;map-to />
              &lt;field>
                  &lt;sql />
              &lt;/field>
              ...
          &lt;/class>
      &lt;/mapping>
      </code>

      <p>
      Each EntityBean and dependent Java object is represented by a &lt;class> element 
      composed of attributes, a &lt;map-to> element and &lt;field> elements. The &lt;map-to> element
      contains a reference to the relational table to which the EntityBean maps. 
      Each &lt;field> element represents either a public class variable or a the 
      variable's accessor/mutator methods (depending upon the mapping info). Each 
      &lt;field> element is composed of attributes and one &lt;sql> element. 
      The &lt;sql> element represents the field in the relational table to which 
      the &lt;field> element maps. 
      </p>

    </section> 

    <section title="The Mapping File">
      
      <section title="The &lt;class> element  "> 

<code>
&lt;!ELEMENT class ( description?, cache-type?, map-to?, field+ )>
&lt;!ATTLIST class
          name            ID       #REQUIRED
          extends         IDREF    #IMPLIED
          depends         IDREF    #IMPLIED
          auto-complete   ( true |false ) "false"
          identity        CDATA    #IMPLIED
          access          ( read-only | shared | exclusive | db-locked )  "shared"
          key-generator   IDREF    #IMPLIED >
</code>


        <p>
        The  &lt;class> element contains all the information used to map a EntityBean 
        to a relational database. The content of &lt;class> is mainly used to describe 
        the fields that will be mapped.
        </p>

        <p>
        Description of the attributes:
        </p>

        <ul>
          <li><b>name:</b> The fully qualified package name of the EntityBean or dependent Java object to map to.</li>

          <li><b>extends:</b> Should be used _only_ if this EntityBean or dependent Java object extends another Java
          object for which mapping information is provided. It should _not_ be used if the 
          extended Java object is not referenced in the mapping file.</li>

          <li><b>depends:</b> For more information on this field, please see 
          <a href="http://castor.exolab.org/castor-one.html#Dependent-and-related-relationships">
          Dependent and related relationships</a>.</li>

          <li><b>identity:</b> For more information on this field, please see 
          <a href="http://castor.exolab.org/design-persist.html#Persistence">Design -> Persistence</a>.</li>

          <li><b>access:</b> For more information on this field, please see 
          <a href="http://castor.exolab.org/locking.html#Locking-Modes">Locking Modes</a>.</li>
          
          <li><b>key-generator</b>: For more information on this field, please see 
          <a href="http://castor.exolab.org/key-generator.html">KeyGen</a>.</li>
        </ul>

        <p>Description of the elements:</p>

        <ul>
             <li><b>&lt;description></b>: An optional description.</li>

             <li><b>&lt;cache-type></b>: For more information on this field please see 
             <a href="http://castor.exolab.org/long-transact.html#Bounded-dirty-checking">Bounded Dirty Checking</a> 
             and <a href="http://castor.exolab.org/castor-one.html#LRU-Cache">LRU Cache</a>.</li>

             <li><b>&lt;map-to></b>: Used to tell the CMP Container the name of the relational 
             table to which to map.</li>

             <li><b>&lt;field></b>: Zero or more &lt;field> elements are used to describe properties 
             of each EntityBean or dependent Java object.</li>
        </ul>

      </section>

      <section title="The &lt;map-to> element">

<code>
&lt;!ELEMENT map-to EMPTY>
&lt;!ATTLIST map-to
          table      NMTOKEN  #IMPLIED
          xml        NMTOKEN  #IMPLIED
          ns-uri     NMTOKEN  #IMPLIED
          ns-prefix  NMTOKEN  #IMPLIED
          ldap-dn    NMTOKEN  #IMPLIED
          ldap-oc    NMTOKEN  #IMPLIED>
</code>

        <p>&lt;map-to> is used to specify the name of the item that should be associated
          with the given EntityBean or dependent Java object. The &lt;map-to> element is only used for the root 
          Java object.</p>

        <p>Description of the attributes:</p>

        <ul>
          <li><b>table:</b> The name of the relational database table to which the 
          EntityBean or dependent Java object is associated.</li>
        </ul>

      </section>


      <section title="The &lt;field> element">

<code>
&lt;!ELEMENT field ( description?, sql?, xml?, ldap? )>
&lt;!ATTLIST field
          name           NMTOKEN  #REQUIRED
          type           NMTOKEN  #IMPLIED
          required       ( true | false )  "false"
          direct         ( true | false )  "false"
          lazy           ( true | false )  "false"
          transient      ( true | false )  "false"
          get-method     NMTOKEN  #IMPLIED
          set-method     NMTOKEN  #IMPLIED
          create-method  NMTOKEN  #IMPLIED
          collection     ( array | vector | hashtable | collection | set | map )  #IMPLIED>
</code> 

        <p>The &lt;field> element is used to describe a property of a EntityBean or dependent Java object. It provides:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>the object's identity ('name')</li>
          <li>the object's type (inferred from 'type' and 'collection')</li>
          <li>the object's access method (inferred from 'direct', 'get-method', 'set-method')</li>
        </ul>

        <p>From this information, the CMP Container is able to access a given property in the EntityBean or dependent Java
          object.</p>

        <p>In order to determine the signature that the CMP Container expects, there are two easy
          rules to apply.</p>

        <p><b>1. Determine &lt;type>.</b></p> 

        <ul>
          <li><p><b>If there is no 'collection' attribute</b>, the object type is the the value 
          of the 'type' attribute. The value of the type attribute can be a fully qualified Java 
          object like 'java.lang.String' or one of the allowed aliases:</p>

            <table border="1" cellpadding="4">
              <tr><th>short name</th><th>Primitive type?</th><th>Java Class</th></tr>
              <tr><td>other</td><td>N</td><td>java.lang.Object</td></tr>
              <tr><td>string</td><td>N</td><td>java.lang.String</td></tr>
              <tr><td>integer</td><td>Y</td><td>java.lang.Integer.TYPE</td></tr>
              <tr><td>long</td><td>Y</td><td>java.lang.Long.TYPE</td></tr>
              <tr><td>boolean</td><td>Y</td><td>java.lang.Boolean.TYPE</td></tr>
              <tr><td>double</td><td>Y</td><td>java.lang.Double.TYPE</td></tr>
              <tr><td>float</td><td>Y</td><td>java.lang.Float.TYPE</td></tr>
              <tr><td>big-decimal</td><td>N</td><td>java.math.BigDecimal</td></tr>
              <tr><td>byte</td><td>Y</td><td>java.lang.Byte.TYPE</td></tr>
              <tr><td>date</td><td>N</td><td>java.util.Date</td></tr>
              <tr><td>short</td><td>Y</td><td>java.lang.Short.TYPE</td></tr>
              <tr><td>char</td><td>Y</td><td>java.lang.Character.TYPE</td></tr>
              <tr><td>bytes</td><td>N</td><td>byte[]</td></tr>
              <tr><td>chars</td><td>N</td><td>char[]</td></tr>
              <tr><td>strings</td><td>N</td><td>String[]</td></tr>                
              <tr><td>locale</td><td>N</td><td>java.util.Locale</td></tr>
            </table>

            <p>the CMP Container will try to cast the data in the mapping file to the proper Java 
            type.</p></li>


          <li><p><b>If there is a collection attribute</b>, the items in the following table can be
          used:</p>

            <table border="1" cellpadding="4">
              <tr><th>name</th><th>type</th><th>default implementation</th></tr>
              <tr><td>array</td><td>&lt;type_attribute>[]</td><td>&lt;type_attribute>[]</td></tr>
              <tr><td>vector</td><td>java.util.Vector</td><td>java.util.Vector</td></tr>
              <tr><td>hashtable</td><td>java.util.Hashtable</td><td>java.util.Hashtable</td></tr>
              <tr><td>collection</td><td>java.util.Collection</td><td>java.util.Arraylist </td></tr>
              <tr><td>arraylist</td><td>java.util.ArrayList</td><td>java.util.Arraylist </td></tr>
              <tr><td>set</td><td>java.util.Set</td><td>java.util.Hashset</td></tr>
              <tr><td>map</td><td>java.util.Map</td><td>java.util.Hashmap</td></tr>
            </table>

            <p>The type of the object inside the collection is the 'type' attribute. The 'default
              implementation' is the type used if the object holding the collection is found
              to be null and needs to be instantiated.</p>

            <p>For hashtable and map, the CMP Container will add an object using the put(object, object) 
            method - the object is both the key and the value. This will be improved in the future.</p></li>
        </ul>

        <p>It is necessary to use a collection when the content model of the element expects more 
        than one element of the specified type. This is how the 'to-many' portion of a relationship 
        is described.</p>


        <p><b>2. Determine the signature of the method</b></p>

        <li><p><b>If 'direct' is set to true</b>, the CMP Container expects to find a public EntityBean or dependent Java 
        object variable with the given signature:</p>

        <code>
        public &lt;type> &lt;name>;
        </code>

            <li><p><b>If 'direct' is set to false or omitted</b>, the CMP Container will access the property
            though accessor methods. the CMP Container determines the signature of the accessors and mutators 
            as follows: If the 'get-method' or 'set-method' attributes are supplied, it will
            try to find a function with the following signature:</p>

            <code>
            public &lt;type> &lt;get-method>();
            </code>
            or
            <code>
            public void &lt;set-method>(&lt;type> value);
            </code>

            <p>If 'get-method' or 'set-method' attributes are not provided, the CMP Container will try to
            find the following function:</p>

            <code>
            public &lt;type> get&lt;capitalized-name>();
            </code>
            or
            <code>
            public void set&lt;capitalized-name>(&lt;type> value);
            </code>
            
            <p>&lt;capitalized-name> means that the CMP Container uses the &lt;name> attribute by changing its first
            letter to uppercase without modifying the other letters.</p>

            <p>The content of the &lt;field> element will contain the information about how to map 
            this field to the relational table.</p>
          </li>
        </li>

        <p>Description of the attributes: </p>

        <ul>
          <li><b>name:</b> If 'direct' access is used, 'name' should be the name of a public
          variable in the object we are mapping (the field must be public, not
          static and not transient). If no direct access and no 'get-/set-method'
          is specified, this name will be used to infer the name of the accessor and 
          mutator methods.</li>

          <li><b>type:</b> The Java type of the field. This is used to access the
          field. The CMP Container will use this information to cast the data type(e.g. string 
          into integer). It is also used to define the signature of the accessor and 
          mutator methods. If a collection is specified, this is used to specify the 
          type of the object inside the collection. See description above for more 
          details.</li>

          <li><b>required:</b> If true, the field is not optional.</li>

          <!--
          <li><b>transient:</b> If true, this field will be ignored during the
          marshalling. This is usefull in when used with the auto-complete
          option.</li>
          -->

          <li><b>direct:</b> If true, the CMP Container expects a public variable in the object
          and will modify it directly.</li>

          <li><b>collection:</b> If a parent object expects more than one occurrence of
          one of its fields, it is necessary to specify which collection type the CMP Container will 
          use to handle them. The type specified is used to define the type of the 
          content inside the collection.</li>

          <li><b>get-method:</b> An optional name of the accessor method the CMP Container should 
          use. If this attribute is not set, the CMP Container will try to guess the name with the
          algorithm described above.</li>


          <li><b>set-method:</b> An optional name of the mutator method the CMP Container should 
          use. If this attribute is not set, the CMP Container will try to guess the name with the
          algorithm described above.</li>

          <li><b>create-method:</b> Factory method for instantiation of the object.</li>
        </ul>

      </section>

      <section title="The &lt;sql> element">

          <p>
<code>
&lt;!ELEMENT sql EMPTY>
&lt;!ATTLIST sql
    name        NMTOKENS  #IMPLIED
    type        NMTOKENS  #IMPLIED
    many-key    NMTOKENS  #IMPLIED
    many-table  NMTOKEN   #IMPLIED
    read-only   ( true | false )    "false"
    dirty       ( check | ignore )  "check">

</code>
          </p>
  
          <p>
          The &lt;sql> element is used to denote information about the relational
          database table to which a EntityBean and dependent Java object is mapped. 
          It should be declared 
          for all &lt;field> elements. Each &lt;field> element contains one &lt;sql> 
          element. The &lt;sql> element pertains directly to the the &lt;map-to> 
          element for the containing &lt;class> element. The &lt;sql> elements 
          contains the following attributes: 

          <ul>
            <li><b>name:</b> The column name in the relational database table.</li>
  
            <li><b>type:</b> The column type in the relational database table.</li>
  
            <li><b>many-key:</b> Specifies the name of the column that holds the 
            foreign key of the containing object. Used _only_ for 'to-many' relations.</li>
  
            <li><b>many-table:</b> Specifies the name of the bridge table that contains
            the primary keys of the object on each side of the relationship.</li>
  
            <li><b>read-only:</b> If true, the column in the relational database
            table will only be read, not updated or deleted.</li>
  
            <li><b>dirty:</b> If the value is 'ignore', the field will not be checked
            against the database for modification.</li>
          </ul>
          </p>

      </section>

    </section>


    <section title="Usage Pattern">

      <p>Here is an example of a mapping file and the corresponding EntityBean and dependent Java object and
      DDL for the databse table.</p>

        <p>The following is an example Java object:</p>

        <table border="1" cellpadding="4">
            <tr>
                <td BGCOLOR="#CCCCCC">
                    <code>
package myapp;

public class Product implements javax.ejb.EntityBean
{
    private int       _id;

    private String    _name; 

    private float     _price; 

    private ProductGroup _group;


    public int getId()
    ...

    public void setId( int anId )
    ...

    public String getName()
    ...

    public void setName( String aName )
    ...

    public float getPrice()
    ...

    public void setPrice( float aPrice )
    ...

    public ProductGroup getProductGroup()
    ...

    public void setProductGroup( ProductGroup aProductGroup )
    ...
}
                    </code>
                  </td>
              </tr>
        </table>

        <p>The following is the relational database table:</p>
        
        <table border="1" cellpadding="4">
            <tr>
                <td BGCOLOR="#CCCCCC">
                    <code>
create table prod 
(
  id        int           not null,
  name      varchar(200)  not null,
  price     numeric(18,2) not null,
  group_id  int           not null
);
                    </code>
                  </td>
              </tr>
        </table>

        <p>The following is the mapping file for the example EntityBean:</p>

        <table border="1" cellpadding="4">
            <tr>
                <td BGCOLOR="#CCCCCC">
                    <code>
&lt;?xml version="1.0"?>
&lt;!DOCTYPE mapping PUBLIC "-//EXOLAB/Castor Object Mapping DTD Version 1.0//EN"
                         "http://castor.exolab.org/mapping.dtd">
&lt;mapping>

    &lt;class name="myapp.Product" identity="id">

        &lt;map-to table="prod" />

        &lt;field name="id" type="integer">
            &lt;sql name="id" type="integer" />
        &lt;/field>

        &lt;field name="name" type="string">
            &lt;sql name="name" type="char" />
        &lt;/field>

        &lt;field name="price" type="float">
            &lt;sql name="price" type="numeric" />
        &lt;/field>

        &lt;field name="group" type="myapp.ProductGroup" >
            &lt;sql name="group_id" />
        &lt;/field>

    &lt;/class>

&lt;/mapping>

                    </code>
                  </td>
              </tr>
        </table>

    </section>

  </body>
</document>
