<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- $Id$ -->
<!-- This file contains a list of OpenEJB contributors -->
<document url="http://openejb.sf.net/contributors.xml">
  <body>
    <title>The OpenEJB Team</title>
    
    <section title="">
<contributors>

  <contributor type="Committer">
    <name surname="Blevins" given="David"/>
    <role>OpenEJB Co-Founder, Project Lead</role>
    <email>david.blevins@visi.com</email>
    <description>
        David Blevins is author of "Understanding J2EE", a forthcoming Addison-Wesley 
        book on the Java 2 Enterprise Edition, and a contributing author to the book 
        "Component-Based Software Engineering" (Addison-Wesley 2001). David is also 
        the co-founder of the OpenEJB open source Enterprise JavaBeans container system.  David can be found
        speaking about EJB and OpenEJB at conferences such the Exolab Sessions, O'Reilly 
        Enterprise Java Conference, O'Reilly Open Source Convention and JavaOne.
    </description>
  </contributor>
  
  <contributor type="Committer">
    <name surname="Monson-Haefel" given="Richard"/>
    <role>OpenEJB Founder</role>
    <email>richard@monson-haefel.com</email>
    <description>
        Richard Monson-Haefel is a leading expert on Enterprise JavaBeans. He is the
        author of the book Enterprise JavaBeans, 3rd Edition (O'Reilly 2001) and
        co-author of the book Java Message Service (O'Reilly 2000). Mr. Monson-Haefel
        has consulted as an architect on Enterprise JavaBeans, CORBA, Java RMI, and
        other distributed computing projects and is the co-architect of OpenEJB.
    </description>
  </contributor>

  <contributor type="Committer">
    <name surname="Cabrera" given="Alan"/>
    <email>adc@toolazydogs.com</email>
    <company id=""/>
    <description>
      All around good guy to have on your side.  Alan has taken his place among 
      the ranks of OpenEJB developers and dedicates himself to anything that needs
      to be done.  His strengths are versatility, leadership and dedication.
    </description>
  </contributor>

  <contributor type="Committer">
    <name surname="Reich" given="Stefan"/>
    <email>sreich@apple.com</email>
    <company id=""/>
    <description>
    Stefan is a real "hard hitter" on the OpenEJB project, bringing with
    him not only the solid feedback we've always wanted, but code to back
    it all up!  Stefan rounds out the team nicely and does a great job of
    finding those dusty areas that have gone ignored.
    </description>
  </contributor>
  
  <contributor type="Committer">
    <name surname="Haischt" given="Daniel"/>
    <email>sirabyss@gmx.net</email>
    <company id=""/>
    <description>
      Daniel has been hanging out on the dev list for quite some time.  Recently, 
      he has made his very distingushable mark all over our build system by 
      completely cleaning, reorganizing, modularizing, and completing all those 
      little things that never seem to get done. We can expect more great enchancements
      from Daniel in the future.  His strengths are persistence and extreme 
      organizational skills -- even his emails are specially formatted.
    </description>
  </contributor>

  <contributor type="Committer">
    <name surname="Mulder" given="Aaron"/>
    <email>ammulder@alumni.princeton.edu</email>
    <company id=""/>
    <description>
    Creator of the Modern Assembler and Hot Deploy functionality
    </description>
  </contributor>

  <contributor type="Feedback">
    <name surname="Cabot" given="Toby"/>
    <email>toby@caboteria.org</email>
    <company id=""/>
    <description>
    Our friend from the north, as Alan calls him. Toby is a regular on the dev 
    list and is always giving us good feedback on the various issues that come
    in the list.  Maybe if people lean on him a bit, we can turn him into one
    of the projects contributors ;)
    </description>
  </contributor>

  <contributor type="Committer">
    <name surname="Chen" given="Pizer"/>
    <email>pizerc@utstar.com</email>
    <company id=""/>
    <description>
    Another friend from the testing efforts of the summer.  Pizer still comes 'round to 
    give new functionality a spin and tell us what goes wrong.
    </description>
  </contributor>
  
  <!--
      Company Information, so we don't have to duplicate it for
      mulitple contributors of the same company
  -->
  
  <!-- description of contributor types -->

  <type name="Committer">
    Committers are contributors who have written lots of important code,
    sacrificing all social events, and becoming a hermit at the expense
    of providing good tools for people they don't even know. In return for
    their love and devotion you may bug them with questions, bug fixes,
    patches and offer them free beer.
  </type>
  
  <type name="Feedback">
    The following have offered valuable feedback (including bug reports) that has been beneficial
    to the development and stability.
  </type>

</contributors>
</section>
</body></document>
