<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- This file contains a list of OpenEJB contributors -->
<document url="http://openejb.exolab.org/contributors.xml">
  <body>
    <title>Contributors</title>
    <header>
    <p><span class="header">Richard Monson-Haefel</span> - Founder</p><p>
        <span class="bodyBlack">
        Richard Monson-Haefel is a leading expert on Enterprise JavaBeans. He is the
        author of the book Enterprise JavaBeans, 2nd Edition (O'Reilly 2000) and
        co-author of the book Java Message Service (O'Reilly 2000). Mr. Monson-Haefel
        has consulted as an architect on Enterprise JavaBeans, CORBA, Java RMI, and
        other distributed computing projects and is the lead architect of OpenEJB.
        </span></p>
    <p><span class="header">David Blevins</span> - Co-Founder</p><p>
        <span class="bodyBlack">
        David Blevins is a contributing author to the book 'Component-Based Software 
        Engineering' (Addison-Wesley 2001) and author of a forthcoming Addison-Wesley
        book on the Java 2 Enterprise Edition. David is also the co-founder of the 
        OpenEJB open source Enterprise JavaBeans container system.  David can be found
        speaking about EJB and OpenEJB at conferences such the Exolab Sessions, O'Reilly 
        Enterprise Java Conference, O'Reilly Open Source Convention and JavaOne.
        </span></p>
    </header>
    
    <section title="">
<contributors>

  <contributor type="Committer">
    <name surname="Monson-Haefel" given="Richard"/>
    <email>rmh@intalio.com</email>
    <company id="intalio"/>
    <description>
      OpenEJB Founder
    </description>
  </contributor>

  <contributor type="Committer">
    <name surname="Blevins" given="David"/>
    <email>david.blevins@visi.com</email>
    <company id="intalio"/>
    <description>
      OpenEJB Co-Founder
    </description>
  </contributor>

  <contributor type="Committer">
    <name surname="Mulder" given="Aaron"/>
    <email>ammulder@alumni.princeton.edu</email>
    <company id=""/>
    <description>
    Creator of the Modern Assembler and Hot Deploy functionality
    </description>
  </contributor>

  <contributor type="Committer">
    <name surname="Cabrera" given="Alan"/>
    <email>adc@toolazydogs.com</email>
    <company id=""/>
    <description>
      All around good guy to have on your side.  Alan has taken his place among 
      the ranks of OpenEJB developers and dedicates himself to anything that needs
      to be done.  His strengths are versatility, leadership and dedication.
    </description>
  </contributor>

  <contributor type="Contributor">
    <name surname="Haischt" given="Daniel"/>
    <email>sirabyss@gmx.net</email>
    <company id=""/>
    <description>
      Daniel has been hanging out on the dev list for quite some time.  Recently, he has made his 
      very distingushable mark all over our build system by completely cleaning, reorganizing, 
      modularizing, and completing all those little things that never seem to get done. We can 
      expect more great enchancements from Daniel in the future.  His strengths are persistence 
      and extreme organizational skills -- even his emails are specially formatted.
    </description>
  </contributor>

  <contributor type="Feedback">
    <name surname="Cabot" given="Toby"/>
    <email>toby@caboteria.org</email>
    <company id=""/>
    <description>
    Our friend from the north, as Alan calls him. Toby is a regular on the dev 
    list and is always giving us good feedback on the various issues that come
    in the list.  Maybe if people lean on him a bit, we can turn him into one
    of the projects contributors ;)
    </description>
  </contributor>

  <contributor type="Feedback">
    <name surname="Gangadhar" given="Mukesh"/>
    <email>opensrc_inf@yahoo.com</email>
    <company id=""/>
    <description>
    One of our friends from the testing team that was learning the container 
    system this summer. Mukesh has been on the dev list for quite some time and
    is great for asking questions that most are too shy to ask.
    </description>
  </contributor>
  
  <contributor type="Feedback">
    <name surname="Chen" given="Pizer"/>
    <email>pizerc@utstar.com</email>
    <company id=""/>
    <description>
    Another friend from the testing efforts of the summer.  Pizer still comes 'round to 
    give new functionality a spin and tell us what goes wrong.
    </description>
  </contributor>
  
  <!--
      Company Information, so we don't have to duplicate it for
      mulitple contributors of the same company
  -->
  <company id="intalio">
    <name>Intalio, Inc.</name>
    <url>www.intalio.com</url>
  </company>



  <!-- description of contributor types -->

  <type name="Committer">
    Committers are contributors who have written lots of important code,
    sacrificing all social events, and becoming a hermit at the expense
    of providing good tools for people they don't even know. In return for
    their love and devotion you may bug them with questions, bug fixes,
    patches and offer them free beer.
  </type>

  <type name="Contributor">
    Contributors are responsible for making this a better project and
    we all end up benefiting from the bug fixes, design changees or features
    they contributed. Contributors tend to live a balanced life and
    hopefully eat a healthy diet.
  </type>

  <type name="Documentor">
    Documentors do the impossible and actually explain how to use the
    software in spite of all the complexity introduced by the committers
    and contributors.
  </type>

  <type name="Feedback">
    The following have offered valuable feedback (including bug reports) that has been beneficial
    to the development and stability.
  </type>

</contributors>
</section>
</body></document>
