<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- $Id$ -->
<document url="http://openejb.sf.net/cvs-faq.xml">
  <body>
    <title>CVS FAQ</title>

    <section title="What is CVS?" ref-id="whatiscvs">
    
    <p>
    The Concurrent Versions System (CVS) provides network-transparent source
    control for groups of developers.  CVS has four basic functions:
    </p>
    
    <ul>
    <LI>Maintains a history of all changes made to each directory tree it manages</LI>
    <LI>Provides hooks to support process control and change control</LI>
    <LI>Provides reliable access to its directory trees from remote hosts using Internet protocols</LI>
    <LI>Supports parallel development allowing more than one developer to work on the same sources at the same time</LI>
    </ul>          
    
    <p>
    All the OpenEJB source code, documentation, and other files are in a CVS
    repository on a server at SourceForge.  To access the repository and 
    download the source code and other files, you need a cvs client.
    </p>
    </section> 
    
    <section title="Where can I get CVS?" ref-id="whereiscvs">
    <p>
    If you are on a Linux machine, you most likely already have cvs.  To 
    find out if cvs is intalled, type the following command at a prompt:
    <br/><br/>
    <command>which cvs</command>
    </p>    
    
    <p>
    If you are one a Windows machine, you will need to download the CVS command-line 
    client <a href="http://ftp.cvshome.org/win32/cvs1-11-1p1.zip">for Windows</a>.
    </p>    
      
    <p>    
    The CVS command line client is available on many operating systems. 
    Choose the CVS client that's right for your OS at the official 
    <a href="http://www.cvshome.org/downloads.html">CVS download</a>  
    page.
    </p>    
    </section> 
    
    <section title="How do I install CVS?" ref-id="installingcvs">
    <p>
    There is no "Install Shield" for cvs. You just put the cvs executable in
    any directory and then include that directory in your PATH system     
    variable. Then you can execute cvs commands from anywhere in your 
    command shell.  
    </p>    

    <section title="Set the PATH variable" ref-id="path">
    <p>
    To set the PATH variable on a Windows machine, execute the following command 
    in a command prompt.<br/><br/>
    <command>set PATH=%PATH%;C:\the\path\where\cvs\is</command>
    </p>    
    </section>
    
    <section title="Set the CVSROOT variable" ref-id="cvsroot">
    <p>
    To execute cvs commands against a CVS repository, you must 
    tell cvs where the repository is by setting its location in a CVSROOT 
    evironment variable, or by specifying it in your command with the cvs -d option.
    </p>    

    <p>
    To set the CVSROOT variable on a Windows machine so that it points toward
    the OpenEJB cvs at SourceForge, execute the following command in a command 
    prompt.<br/><br/>
    <command>set CVSROOT=:pserver:anonymous@cvs.openejb.sf.net:/cvsroot/openejb</command>
    </p>    
    </section>

    <section title="Set the HOME variable" ref-id="home">
    <p>
    The first time you access a particular CVS repository, you must first login 
    to the server hosting the repository.  You can do this with the 'cvs login' 
    command, but before doing this you need to set another environment variable.  
    CVS needs to know where to put your login information, for this you must set 
    the HOME environment variable on your OS or in your shell.<br/><br/>
    If you are on a Linux/Unix machine, this will already be set, but if you are
    on a Windows machine, you will most likely need to do this manually.
    </p>    
    
    <p>
    To set the HOME variable on a Windows machine, execute the following command 
    in a command prompt.<br/><br/>
    <command>set HOME=C:\any\directory\works</command>
    </p>    
    </section> 
    </section>
 
   </body>
</document>
