<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- $Id$ -->
<document url="http://openejb.sf.net/cvs_for_the_impatient.xml">
  <body>
    <title>CVS for the impatient</title>
  
    <section title="Download the source code">
      <p>
      Most of the users probably do not need access to the source code on
      a day by day basis. This is especially true if you need a OpenEJB
      system based on rock solid source code instead of bleading edge
      features.
      </p>
      
      <p>
      As soon as we publish our first major release to the public
      you can download a source and a binary version of OpenEJB
      at the sourceforge <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/openejb/">download page</a>.
      </p>      
    </section>
  
    <section title="Accessing the CVS repository via AnonCVS">
      <p>
      There are two methods of accessing the CVS source repository to get the code
      with bleading edge features. The first one is called <i>anonymous access</i>
      and is available to everyone via a anonymous user. The second one is only
      available to active OpenEJB developers.
      </p>
      
      <p>
      As mentioned earlier, everybody is allowed to checkout the complete OpenEJB
      source code via a anonymous user/password pair. To do, simply type the following
      commands at your command prompt. If you are using a GUI client you have to configure
      'em appropriate.
      </p>
      
      <p>
      <pre><![CDATA[
      cvs -d:pserver:anonymous@cvs.openejb.sf.net:/cvsroot/openejb login
      ]]></pre>
      </p>
      
      <p>
      <pre><![CDATA[
      cvs -d:pserver:anonymous@cvs.openejb.sf.net:/cvsroot/openejb checkout openejb
      ]]></pre>
      </p>
    </section>
  
    <section title="Accessing the CVS repository with full write privilegs">
      <p>
      Real OpenEJB <i>committers</i> have a login on the sourceforge CVS server.
      If you are not a committer but want to submit patches or even want to request commit
      privilegs, you have to follow several guidelines. Please see our contributor 
      <a href="contributor_guidlines.html">guidlines</a> for more information.
      </p>
      
      <p>
      To use your login on the sourceforge CVS server, you have to follow one
      of the links below, depending on the type of your operationg system.
      </p>
      
      <p>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="cvs_ssh_unix_guideline.html">UNIX</a></li>
          <li><a href="cvs_ssh_windows_guideline.html">Windows</a></li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
