<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- $Id$ -->
<document url="http://openejb.sf.net/datasheet.xml">
  <body>
    <title>Technical Overview</title>

    <section title="Overview">

      <p>
The Enterprise JavaBeans (EJB) architecture is a component architecture
for the development and deployment of component-based distributed business 
applications. Applications written using the Enterprise JavaBeans architecture
are scalable, transactional, and multi-user secure. OpenEJB is an Open Source 
implementation of version 1.1 of the EJB specification, which supports both 
session and entity beans in addition to an enhanced security model.


     </p>

    </section>

    <section title="Container-Server Contract">

      <p>
OpenEJB is a pre-built, self-contained, portable EJB container system that can 
be plugged into any application server environment. OpenEJB provides a clear 
separation of responsibilities between the EJB container and the EJB server. 
The application server and OpenEJB container system interact through an open 
programming interface, which forms the container-server contact. This contract 
is defined by the Container Provider Interface (CPI), which is a small and 
simple set of classes and interfaces.
     </p>

    </section>

    <section title="Application Server's Role">


      <p>
Application servers that use OpenEJB are responsible for providing client applications
with naming and remote access to the application server. Its services may include 
providing JNDI and proxy implementations that fulfill the client-server contract of the 
EJB programming model. In application servers that use OpenEJB locally, such as a 
Servlet Container, OpenEJB already provides the necessary JNDI and proxy 
implementations. When a client makes a request on a remote bean reference, the 
application server delivers the request to the OpenEJB container system, which delegates
the request to the appropriate enterprise bean and applies the transaction, security, and
persistence services appropriately.
     </p>

    </section>

    <section title="Container's Role">

      <p>
OpenEJB manages the enterprise bean's lifecycle and coordinates the application 
of transactions (local or distributed), persistence, and security as defined by 
the EJB specification. To manage these tasks in a way that is flexible and 
customizable, OpenEJB also enforces a separation of these responsibilities into 
separate services. OpenEJB provides a Service Provider Interface (SPI) for 
transaction, persistence, and security services. These simple and flexible 
container-service contracts are based on simple adapters and industry standards 
like JTS and JAAS.
     </p>

    </section>

    <section title="OpenEJB Architecture">

      <p>
OpenEJB is the first EJB container system that allows developers of an EJB 
platform to assemble it from existing products rather than construct it from 
scratch. Vendors focus on what they do best while OpenEJB provides the container 
to host Enterprise JavaBeans. When plugged into any Java compatible application 
server, the result is a complete, yet modular Enterprise JavaBeans container 
system. Through the CPI, an application server vendor can use the OpenEJB container 
system to obtain an instant and customizable EJB 1.1 platform. Through the SPI, 
primary services may be interchanged to match any target environment's specific 
requirements.

     </p>

    </section>



    <section title="Containers">

      <p>
The OpenEJB container system provides four robust container types, including stateless 
and stateful session-bean containers as well as Bean-Managed (BMP) and Container-Managed 
(CMP) entity-bean containers. These containers are strictly compliant with the EJB 1.1 
specification, and provide the full complement of security and transaction behaviors to 
beans. The OpenEJB containers are very lightweight because they multiplex requests 
concurrently, requiring less overhead to service more beans. The containers are also 
extremely fast because they introduce virtually no bottlenecks to service requests, 
allowing a high volume of requests to execute within the container system simultaneously.
     </p>

    </section>



  <section title="Primary Services">

      <p>
OpenEJB defines four primary services: transaction, security, persistence, and assembly.
The first three are used continually at runtime by the container system. The last is 
used only at startup to assemble the container system. The containers use the 
transaction, security, and persistence services while servicing beans and performing 
other responsibilities: the transaction service provides the container with 
transactional integrity; the security service provides authorization control; the 
persistence service provides an API for container-managed persistence of entity beans.
     </p>

    </section>

 <section title="IntraVM Server">

      <p>
OpenEJB includes an IntraVM server that allows for swift interaction among beans in the 
same virtual machine. While respecting the remote semantics required by EJB, optimizations
in method calls from one bean to another provide for very fast throughput and little or 
no latency. The IntraVM provides an immediately available platform for application servers 
that do not need to support client access through distributed objects. For example, an 
existing Servlet Container can use the IntraVM server to integrate the OpenEJB container
system with very little effort.
     </p>
    </section>
  
  </body>
</document>
