<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- $Id$ -->
<faqs>
    <super id="faq">FAQ</super>
    <name>FAQ</name>

    <introduction>
       <p>
        FAQ list:<br/>
        <a href="faq_general.html">General FAQ</a><br/>
        <a href="faq_errors.html">Errors FAQ</a><br/>
        <a href="faq_support.html">Support FAQ</a><br/>
        <a href="faq_cmp.html">CMP Entity FAQ</a><br/>
        <a href="faq_servlets.html">Servlets FAQ</a><br/>
        <a href="faq_mysql.html">MySQL FAQ</a><br/>
        <a href="faq_oracle.html">Oracle FAQ</a><br/>
        <a href="faq_openejb-jar.html">openejb-jar.xml file FAQ</a><br/>
        </p>
        <p>
            There are times when we all get stuck and need a little help.
            Hopefully, this FAQ will privide some assistance.  If you still
            don't find the answer to your question, you may want to
            <a href="#support">submit a Support Request</a>.
        </p>
        <p>
            Don't forget to take advantage of our
            <a href="lists.html">mail list groups</a>.
            You'll find that it's an excellent source of help and a great place to
            bounce ideas off of the group.  This list is monitored by the OpenEJB team.
        </p>
    </introduction>
    <faq>
        <question>Errors</question>
        <answer id="errors">
            <p>
                When you're first starting out, some of the error messages that
                OpenEJB prints out may be confusing.  If you're still scratching
                your head, go to the <a href="faq_errors.html">Errors FAQ</a>.
            </p>
        </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <question>What is CVS?</question>
        <answer id="cvs">
            <p>
            Getting involved in any Open Source project requires the source.
            The standard tool for managing source code in open source projects is CVS.
            If you are not familiar with CVS, take a moment to read our
            <a href="faq_cvs.html">CVS FAQ</a>.
            </p>
        </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <question>How do I submit a Support Request?</question>
        <answer id="support">
            <p>
                Sending a support request is one of the many ways that you can
                get some help.  This <a href="faq_support.html">FAQ</a> explains
                the whys and hows of submitting Support Requests.
            </p>
        </answer>
    </faq>
    <faq>
        <question>Can I add to these FAQ documents?</question>
        <answer id="help">
            <p>
            Yes, of course!  Please do!  You can use this simple document
as a <a href="faq_template.xml">template</a>.  Just fill it in and send it
to the <a href="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?func=add&amp;group_id=44351&amp;atid=439276">Patch tracker</a>, it will be up in no time!

            </p>
        </answer>
    </faq>

</faqs>
