<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document url="http://openejb.exolab.org/GSG-1.xml">
    <properties>
        <abstract>
            Abstract
        </abstract>
        <author email="david.blevins@visi.com" ldap="">David Blevins</author>
    </properties>
  <body>
    <title>GSG-1 -- Join the mailing list</title>
    <header>
    <p> 
    <table border="0" cellpadding="0" width="100%">
    <tr><td>OpenEJB - Container System</td><td ALIGN="RIGHT">David Blevins</td></tr>
    <tr><td>Getting Started Guide: GSG-1</td><td ALIGN="RIGHT">February 2001</td></tr>
    </table>
    </p>
    <p><center>Getting Started Guide -- Join the mailing list</center></p>

    <p>Abstract</p><p>

    The mailing list is your connection to all the developers and members of
    the OpenEJB community. This document shows you how to subscribe
    to our main mailing list, the OpenEJB-Dev mailing list. 
    </p>

    <p>Table of Contents</p>

    </header>
    
    <section title="1  Introduction">
      <p>

      The OpenEJB Developer list is where the general OpenEJB community goes to ask questions, make suggestions, chat
      with other users and developers, and keep a finger on the pulse of the project.
      
      </p>

      <p>
      Please feel free to ask as many questions as you need while becoming 
      familiar with the project.  We believe the perspective of those who are new 
      the project is very valuable and we rely on your feedback to make the 
      project easier to use and understand for everyone.  If you have any 
      suggestions on ways we can help those that are new to the project get up to 
      speed more quickly, we are more than willing to listen.
      </p>
    
    </section>
    
    <section title="2  Subscribe">
      <p>                  
      To subscribe to the list send mail to minimalist@exolab.org with 
      "subscribe openejb-dev" in the subject line, with out quotes.

        <UL>
        <LI><a href="mailto:minimalist@exolab.org?subject=subscribe openejb-dev">
           Subscribe</a></LI>
         <LI><a href="http://www.openejb.org/list-archive/">
           View Archive</a></LI>
        </UL>                                                                           
      </p>

    </section>
    
    <section title="3  List Conduct">
    <p>

    <UL>
    <LI>THE GOAL - 
       Everyone must feel free to ask questions and make comments without fear 
       of being attacked, insulted, perceived as stupid, or looked down upon.
    </LI>
    <LI>THE RULE - 
       All opinions, comments and questions are respected, appreciated and 
       welcome.
    </LI>
    
    <LI>THE EXCEPTION TO THE RULE - 
       Posts lacking in patients, decorum or constructiveness will not be 
       tolerated on this list.
    </LI>
    </UL>
   </p>
   </section>


  </body>
</document>
