<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document url="http://openejb.exolab.org/GSG-2.xml">
    <properties>
        <abstract>
            Abstract
        </abstract>
        <author email="david.blevins@visi.com" ldap="">David Blevins</author>
    </properties>
  <body>
    <title>GSG-2 -- Get the source: CVS</title>
    <header>
    <p> 
    <table border="0" cellpadding="0" width="100%">
    <tr><td>OpenEJB - Container System</td><td ALIGN="RIGHT">David Blevins</td></tr>
    <tr><td>Getting Started Guide: GSG-2</td><td ALIGN="RIGHT">February 2001</td></tr>
    </table>
    </p>
    <p><center>Getting Started Guide -- Get the source: CVS</center></p>

    <p>Abstract</p><p>

      Getting involved in any Open Source project requires the source.  This 
      document guides you through the process of getting the OpenEJB 
      project source using the CVS command line client.
    </p>

    <p>Table of Contents</p>

    </header>
    <section title="1  Introduction">
    <a href="GSG-2-TODO.html#TD-0001">[TD-0001]</a>
    </section> 
    
    <section title="2  Get CVS">
    
      <p>
      
      Before we go into getting the source, let's take a second to answer the 
      question, "What is CVS?".
      
      </p>
    </section> 
    
    <section title="2.1  What is CVS">
      
      <p>
    
      The Concurrent Versions System (CVS) provides network-transparent source
      control for groups of developers.  CVS has four basic functions:
      
      </p>
      
      <ul>
        <LI>Maintains a history of all changes made to each directory tree it manages</LI>
        <LI>Provides hooks to support process control and change control</LI>
        <LI>Provides reliable access to its directory trees from remote hosts using Internet protocols</LI>
        <LI>Supports parallel development allowing more than one developer to work on the same sources at the same time</LI>
      </ul>          
      
      <p>
      All the OpenEJB source code, documentation, and other files are in a CVS
      repository an ExoLab server.  To access the repository and download the 
      source code and other files, you need a cvs client.
      </p>
    </section> 
    
    <section title="2.2   Downloading CVS">
      <p>
    
      The CVS client is available on many operating systems. Choose the CVS 
      client that's right for your OS by following on one of the links below:
      
      </p>    
      
      <ul>
        <LI><a href="ftp://ftp.cvshome.org/pub/cvs-1.10.5/windows/cvs.exe">CVS for Windows</a></LI>
        <LI><a href="ftp://ftp.cvshome.org/pub/cvs-1.10.8/bin/cvs">CVS for Linux</a></LI>
      </ul>
      <a href="GSG-2-TODO.html#TD-0002">[TD-0002]</a>
      
      <p>    
      If you don't see your OS listed above, go to the official CVS download  
      page or CVS ftp directory and choose from a complete list of CVS 
      clients. 
    
      </p>    
      <a href="GSG-2-TODO.html#TD-0003">[TD-0003]</a>
    
    </section> 
    
    <section title="2.3   Installing CVS">
      <p>
    
      There is no "Install Shield" for cvs. You just put the cvs executable in
      any directory and then include that directory in your PATH system     
      variable. Then you can execute cvs commands from anywhere in your 
      command shell.
      
      </p>    
    <a href="GSG-2-TODO.html#TD-0004">[TD-0004]</a>
    <a href="GSG-2-TODO.html#TD-0005">[TD-0005]</a>
    <a href="GSG-2-TODO.html#TD-0006">[TD-0006]</a>
  
    </section> 
    
    <section title="3  Downloading the project source">
      <p>
    
      In the CVS world, downloading is referred to as checking out. Before you
      can checkout the OpenEJB source from the repository, you need to login.
    
      </p>    
    </section> 
    
    <section title="3.1  Logging into the ExoLab CVS server">
      <p>
    
      To log into the ExoLab cvs server where the OpenEJB project source
      lives.  Execute the following command in your shell:
      
      </p>    
      <p>    
    
      [prompt]$ cvs -d :pserver:anoncvs@openejb.exolab.org:/cvs/openejb login
      
      </p>    
      
      <p>    
      
      When it prompts you for the CVS password, type "anoncvs" without quotes.
      
      </p>    
      <a href="GSG-2-TODO.html#TD-0007">[TD-0007]</a> 
      <a href="GSG-2-TODO.html#TD-0008">[TD-0008]</a>

    </section> 
    
    <section title="3.2  Checking out the source">
      
      <p>
    
      After you have logged in, you can checkout the source code and execute  
      other CVS commands. To checkout the OpenEJB source, go to the directory 
      where you would like to place the files and execute the following 
      command: 
      
      </p>    
      
      <p>    
    
      [prompt]$ cvs -d :pserver:anoncvs@openejb.exolab.org:/cvs/openejb
      checkout openejb 
      
      </p>    
      
      <p>    
    
      NOTE: The text above should be on one line and executed as one command. 
    
      </p>    
      
      <p>    
      
      When you do a checkout, a copy of the newest files in the repository is 
      downloaded to a directory on your local machine. This is called a 
      working copy and is yours to play with, edit, or manage as you see fit. 
      Changes made to your working copy do not become a permanent part of the 
      repository until they are checked in. 
    
      </p>    
      
      <p>    
      
      When files are checked into the repository, they are uploaded from the 
      working copy on your machine to the CVS repository on the ExoLab server.
      The files then become a permanent part of the repository and can be   
      checked out by anyone. 
    
      </p>    
    </section> 
    
    <section title="3.3  Checking in source files (committing)">
      
      <p>
    
      Checking in files, known as committing, requires special access which is
      granted on an individual basis. If you would like to contribute changes 
      to files or new files, you can email the files to the openejb-dev 
      mailing list for review. 
      
      </p>    
    
    </section> 
    
    <section title="4  Other Resources"><p>
    
      <a href="GSG-2-TODO.html#TD-0009">[TD-0009]</a>
      </p>    
    </section> 
    
    <section title="5  References">
      <p>
      <a href="GSG-2-TODO.html#TD-0010">[TD-0010]</a>
      </p>
    </section>


  </body>
</document>
