<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document url="http://openejb.sf.net/index.xml" toc="none">
  <body>
    <title>OpenEJB -- Open Source EJB Container System</title>


    <section title="Welcome to OpenEJB!">
    <p> 
    We are building the hottest EJB container system in the world! The design 
    is radically different, and the performance is wildly faster than anything 
    else available today. If you've got the guts to think differently, and the 
    brains to make a difference, then we dare you to join us. We double dog 
    dare you! 
    </p>
 
    <section title="What is OpenEJB ?">

    <p>
    OpenEJB is an open source EJB container system. As a container system, 
    OpenEJB works like a big plug-in for middleware servers like Web servers, 
    CORBA servers, and application servers. By plugging in OpenEJB these servers
    obtain instant EJB compliance for hosting Enterprise JavaBeans! 
    <br/><br/>
    OpenEJB is designed for speed and low resource consumption making it a very 
    desirable alternative for middleware providers who want EJB 1.1 compatibility. 
    OpenEJB is already shipping in platforms like Apple Computer's 
    <a href="http://www.apple.com/webobjects/">WebObjects</a> and 
    Exolab's <a href="http://openccm.exolab.org">OpenCCM</a>.  OpenEJB is targeted
    for other middleware platforms including another commercial application server 
    called  <a href="www.intalio.com">n3 </a>, a <a href="http://openorb.exolab.org">
    CORBA ORB</a>, and the <a href="http://jakarta.apache.org">Apache Tomcat </a> server.
    </p>

    </section>


    <section title="Who is working on OpenEJB ?">
    <p>
    
    OpenEJB is the brainchild of Richard Monson-Haefel and David Blevins.  
    Richard is author of 
    <a href="http://www.oreilly.com/catalog/entjbeans3">Enterprise JavaBeans, 3rd Edition</a> (O'Reilly 2001) 
    and co-author of 
    <a href="http://www.oreilly.com/catalog/javmesser">Java Message Service</a> (O'Reilly 2000).  
    David Blevins is author of 'Understanding J2EE' a forthcoming Addison-Wesley book on the Java 2 Enterprise 
    Edition, and contributing author to the book 'Component-Based Software Engineering' (Addison-Wesley 2001). 
    <br/><br/>
    </p>

    </section>
</section>

  </body>
</document>
