<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document url="http://openejb.exolab.org/template.xml">
  <body>
    <title>OpenEJB Mailing Lists</title>

    <header>
      <p> 
      Open Source development is inherently chaotic due the fact that all development
      is decentralized.  Don't get discouraged by that, learn to ask as many questions
      as possible on the mailing lists.  
      </p>
    </header>

 
    <section title="Developer Mailing List : openejb-dev@exolab.org">

      <p>

      Where the general OpenEJB community goes to ask questions, make suggestions, chat
      with other users and developers, and keep a finger on the pulse of the project.
      
      </p>
      
      <p>
      
      Medium volume (possibly more than 5 messages a day) mailing list, dedicated to the
      development of OpenEJB.
      
      </p>
      <p>                  
        <UL>
        <LI><a href="mailto:minimalist@exolab.org?subject=subscribe openejb-dev">
           Subscribe</a></LI>
        <LI><a href="mailto:minimalist@exolab.org?subject=unsubscribe openejb-dev">
           Unsubscribe</a></LI>
        <LI>
           <a href="http://www.openejb.org/list-archive/">
           View Archive</a></LI>
        </UL>
      </p>
    </section>
    
    <section title="CVS Mailing List : openejb-cvs@exolab.org">
      <p>                  
      A mailing list for the OpenEJB CVS repository!
      </p>
      
      <p>
      We have mixed a few of the popular perl scripts for cvs email notification as well as added
      a few features that are all new. This new list and perl script provide you with
      as-it-happens information regarding OpenEJB development. You can now get the scoop
      on the changes that take place in OpenEJB as our team is hard at work in developing
      and refining the OpenEJB container system.
      </p>
            
      <p>
      The emails to the cvs mailing list are generated by the perl script and contain: 
      </p>
      
      <p>  
        <UL>
         <LI> Information about the user performing the cvs commit</LI>
         <LI> A list of files being added, changed, and removed</LI>
         <LI> A log message from the user performing the cvs commit</LI>
         <LI> A diff of the changes made to each file committed</LI>
        </UL>
        
        At this time we would still like to keep all dialog on the openejb-dev list.  
        Questions regarding content sent to the openejb-cvs list should be sent to 
        the developer list for everyone to benefit from.  When quoting email from the openejb-cvs 
        list, please only quote the part of the email that is most relevant to your
        question.
    
        <UL>
        <LI><a href="mailto:minimalist@exolab.org?subject=subscribe openejb-cvs">
           Subscribe</a></LI>
        <LI><a href="mailto:minimalist@exolab.org?subject=unsubscribe openejb-cvs">
           Unsubscribe</a></LI>
        </UL>
      </p>
    </section>

  </body>
</document>
