<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document url="http://openejb.sf.net/quickstart.xml" toc="numeric">
  <body>
    <title>OpenEJB QuickStart Guide</title>

    <section title="Abstract" ref-id="abstract">
        
    <p>
    This document is a slightly verbose quickstart, if you are not interested in all
    the chat and simply want the bare minimum, we offer a 
    <a href="commands-only-windows.html">Commands-Only Guide for Windows Users</a> and a 
    <a href="commands-only-linux.html">Commands-Only Guide for Linux/Unix/Mac OS X Users</a>
    </p>
            
    </section>
    
    <section title="Join the mailing list" ref-id="joinlist">
        
    <p>
    The OpenEJB User list is where the general OpenEJB community goes to ask 
    questions, make suggestions, chat with other users, and keep a finger on 
    the pulse of the project.
    </p>
            
    <p>
    Please feel free to ask as many questions as you need while becoming 
    familiar with the project.  We believe the perspective of those who are new 
    the project is very valuable and we rely on your feedback to make the 
    project easier to use and understand for everyone.  If you have any 
    suggestions on ways we can help those that are new to the project get up to 
    speed more quickly, we are more than willing to listen.
    </p>
        
    <p>
    <a href="http://lists.sourceforge.net/lists/listinfo/openejb-user">Subscribe</a>/<a href="http://www.geocrawler.com/redir-sf.php3?list=openejb-user">View Archive</a>        
    </p>
    
    </section>
    
    <section title="Get the source" ref-id="getsource">
    
    <p>
    Getting involved in any Open Source project requires the source.  The 
    standard tool for managing source code in open source projects is CVS. 
    If you are not familiar with CVS, take a moment to read our 
    <a href="cvs-faq.html">CVS FAQ</a>.
    </p>

    
    <p>    
    If you have cvs already installed and are ready to go, the following commands
    are all you need to get the source. The first command logs you into the system, when 
    it prompts you for the CVS password, simply hit the Enter key.
    </p>    
    <p>    
    <command>cvs -d:pserver:anonymous@cvs.openejb.sf.net:/cvsroot/openejb login</command>
    </p>    
    <p>    
    <command>cvs -z3 -d:pserver:anonymous@cvs.openejb.sf.net:/cvsroot/openejb co openejb</command>
    </p>    
      
    <p>    
    NOTE: The 'cvs ....' commands above should be on one line and executed as one command. 
    </p>    

    <p>    
    If you are a new user to cvs, the above steps may seem overly simplistic to you.
    For a more detailed explanation of the login/checkout process, <a href="quickstart-cvs.html">click here</a>.
    </p>    
      
    </section>
    
    <section title="Building OpenEJB" ref-id="buildsource">
    <p>
    After doing the checkout, there should be a new directory named 'openejb', 
    change to that directory and execute the following command:
    </p>
    
    <p>
    Windows:<br></br>
    <command>[prompt] cd openejb</command>
    <command>[prompt] openejb build</command>
    </p>
    <p>  
    Unix/Linux/Mac OS X:<br></br>
    <command>[prompt] cd openejb</command>
    <command>[prompt] chmod 755 openejb.sh bin/*</command>
    <command>[prompt] ./openejb.sh build</command>
    </p>
    </section>
    
    <section title="Run the test suite" ref-id="runtests">
    <p>
    Now that you have built OpenEJB and other needed jars, it's a
    good to run the test suite and verify that everything is setup.
    Execute the following commands:
    </p>
    
    <p>
    Windows:<br></br>
    <command>[prompt] openejb test</command>
    </p>
    <p>  
    Unix/Linux/Mac OS X:<br></br>
    <command>[prompt] ./openejb.sh test</command>
    </p>
    
    </section>
    
    <section title="Deploy your ejb-jar" ref-id="deployjar">
    <p>
    OpenEJB comes with a command-line tool to help guide you through deploying
    your jars in OpenEJB.  The options are as follows:
    </p>
    
    <p>
    Windows:<br></br>
    <command>[prompt] deploy <i>config-file</i> <i>jar-file</i></command>
    </p>
    <p>  
    Unix/Linux/Mac OS X:<br></br>
    <command>[prompt] ./openejb.sh deploy <i>config-file</i> <i>jar-file</i></command>
    </p>
    
    <p>    
    <i>config-file</i> is the location of the configuration file used to start OpenEJB.
    </p>
    <p>  
    <i>jar-file</i> is the location of the EJB jar file containing the beans you would like to deploy.<br/><br/>
    </p>
    <p>
    Windows Example:<br></br>
    <command>[prompt] openejb deploy conf\default.openejb.conf dist\beans\undeployedBeans.jar</command>
    </p>
    <p>  
    Unix/Linux/Mac OS X Example:<br></br>
    <command>[prompt] ./openejb.sh deploy conf/default.openejb.conf dist/beans/undeployedBeans.jar</command>
    </p>
    <p>    
    NOTE: The text above should be on one line and executed as one command. 
    </p>    
    <p>    
    The above examples actually work!  Go ahead and try them out, you must execute them
    in the same directory you build the source in.  Note, the undeployedBeans.jar was built
    when you ran the build script earlier.
    </p>
    </section>

  </body>
</document>
