<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- $Id$ -->
<document url="http://openejb.sf.net/quickstart-cvs.xml" toc="none">
  <body>
    <title>OpenEJB QuickStart Guide</title>

    <section title="Logging into the CVS server">
    <p>
    In the CVS world, downloading is referred to as checking out. Before you
    can checkout the OpenEJB source from the repository, you need to login.
    To log into the cvs server at SourceForge where the OpenEJB project source
    lives.  Execute the following command in your shell:
    </p>    
    
    <p>    
    <command>cvs -d:pserver:anonymous@cvs.openejb.sf.net:/cvsroot/openejb login</command>
    </p>    
      
    <p>    
    When it prompts you for the CVS password, simply hit the Enter key.
    </p>    
    </section> 
    
    <section title="Checking out the source">
    <p>
    After you have logged in, you can checkout the source code and execute  
    other CVS commands. To checkout the OpenEJB source, go to the directory 
    where you would like to place the files and execute the following 
    command: 
    </p>    
      
    <p>    
    <command>cvs -z3 -d:pserver:anonymous@cvs.openejb.sf.net:/cvsroot/openejb
    co openejb</command>
    </p>    
      
    <p>    
    NOTE: The text above should be on one line and executed as one command. 
    </p>    
      
    <p>    
    When you do a checkout, a copy of the newest files in the repository is 
    downloaded to a directory on your local machine. This is called a 
    working copy and is yours to play with, edit, or manage as you see fit. 
    Changes made to your working copy do not become a permanent part of the 
    repository until they are checked in. 
    </p>    
      
    <p>    
    When files are checked into the repository, they are uploaded from the 
    working copy on your machine to the CVS repository on the ExoLab server.
    The files then become a permanent part of the repository and can be   
    checked out by anyone. 
    </p>    
    </section> 
    
    <section title="Checking in source files (committing)">
    
    <p>
    Checking in files, known as committing, requires special access which is
    granted on an individual basis. If you would like to contribute changes 
    to files or new files, you can email the files to the 
    <a href="lists.html#openejb-dev">OpenEJB Developer</a> mailing list for 
    review. 
    </p>    
    
    </section> 
  </body>
</document>
