<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- $Id$ -->
<document url="http://openejb.sf.net/specification.xml">
  <body>
    <title>OpenEJB Specification</title>
    
    <section title="">
        <p>
        OpenEJB represents a revolution in application server design, a view that application servers should be modular, not monolithic. A modular application server is built from subsystems rather than constructed as one huge, tightly coupled platform. Modularization of application server software allows vendors to focus on their core competencies instead of reinventing every subsystem from scratch to create a complete platform. Not only is modularization possible, OpenEJB makes it a reality.
        </p>
        
        <p>
        OpenEJB is an EJB container system - not a monolithic EJB server - that can be plugged into any application server to make it a fully compliant EJB server. 
        The Enterprise JavaBeans API itself does not specify a separation of responsibilities among the application server, the container, and the primary services (transaction, security, and connectors). As a result, EJB vendors must build proprietary monolithic application servers to support all the subsystems needed for a complete EJB platform.
        </p>
        
        <p>
        OpenEJB clearly defines the separation of its responsibilities as a container system from those of the application server that hosts it, and from the primary services that support it. This decoupling enables vendors of application servers, transaction managers, and providers of security services and connectors to focus on their own specialties, while OpenEJB focuses on delivering a high-speed container system that combines the services into a single EJB platform.
        </p>
        
        <p>
        The OpenEJB specification defines a separation of responsibilities among application server, container, and primary services, and details how OpenEJB provides a powerful container system and a set of programming interfaces that make this modularization possible. 
        </p>
        
        <p>
        Download the OpenEJB Specification
        <UL>
        <LI><a href="spec/OpenEJB_Specification.pdf">OpenEJB_Specification.pdf</a></LI>
        <LI><a href="spec.html">Online HTML Version</a></LI>
        </UL>
        </p>

    </section>



  </body>
</document>
